A Guide to the McGavock Family Papers, 1751-1961
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
Special Collections, Kegley Library, Wytheville Community College
McGavock Family Papers 1751-1961
Special Collections, Kegley Library
1989.1
178 folders.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Shirley McGavock McConnell in 1989.
Biographical/Historical Information
The history of the McGavock Family in America begins with the migration of James McGavock (1728-1812). Born in Antrim, Ireland in 1728, James sailed to Philadelphia around 1755. He left his widowed mother and brother Randal living at the McGavock homestead called Carnton near Glenarm. After venturing through the Great Valley of Virginia, James settled in Rockbridge County, Virginia where he prospered as an innkeeper in Fincastle. In 1760 he married Mary Cloyd (1741-1827); Mary Cloyd McGavock and James McGavock had five sons and five daughters.
Searching for fertile land upon which to build his family estate, James McGavock purchased land in Fort Chiswell in present-day eastern Wythe County, Virginia in 1771. Fort Chiswell prospered as a supply depot for military goods, particularly during the French and Indian War and Revolutionary War. McGavock capitalized on this thriving market by stocking goodly quantities of lead, powder, and flint among other supplies.
Concerned by the growing friction between Great Britain and the American colonies, James McGavock joined a local Committee of Safety in 1775. Committee members often met at the ordinary (tavern) which McGavock had constructed in 1772. On 25 January 1775, he was among numerous Southwest Virginia men who signed the Fincastle Resolutions proclaiming their desire for independence from Great Britain.
With the construction of the Montgomery County courthouse in 1779, McGavock hoped to achieve his dream of building a bustling town in Fort Chiswell. Unfortunately, court officials deemed the location too inaccessible and hilly for town development. As the migration of settlers to Kentucky and beyond increased during the 1780s, however, McGavock enjoyed a lucrative trade supplying the weary pioneers with food, lodging, and supplies. By 1800, Fort Chiswell boasted an ordinary, mill, blacksmith shop, carpentry shop, and store.
While his sons David and Randal settled in Nashville, Tennessee, James McGavock's sons Hugh McGavock (1761-1844), James McGavock (1764-1838), and Joseph McGavock (1780-1833) remained at Fort Chiswell. Although he employed all three sons in his various businesses, James McGavock Sr. left his Fort Chiswell property to James McGavock Jr. after his death in 1812.
James McGavock Jr. continued his father's lodging business while developing Fort Chiswell into a prosperous farm. He married Mary Crockett (1778-1826) in 1799 and had twelve children. James McGavock Jr. passed his Fort Chiswell estate on to his sons Stephen Cloyd McGavock (1807-1880) and Joseph Cloyd McGavock (1812/1813-1886)(nicknamed Cloyd). He died in 1838. James McGavock Jr. was also known as James McGavock Sr. after his father's death.
Stephen McGavock and Joseph Cloyd McGavock successfully ran the Fort Chiswell estate for over four decades. In 1839, they constructed an imposing mansion which features five stories and large Palladian windows. The brothers not only supervised the plantation activities but engaged in land acquisition and development. Stephen McGavock also served on the Board of Directors of the Farmers Bank of Virginia.
Ephraim McGavock (1805-1876), son of James McGavock Jr., settled in Wytheville. In 1840 he married Abigail Jouett Williamson (1812-1877) (nicknamed Abie), a native of New York. Abie McGavock founded a private school for girls in Wytheville at which she served as both principal and teacher. Ephraim McGavock and Abigail Jouett Williamson McGavock had eight children.
Upon Joseph Cloyd McGavock's death in 1885, Ephraim's oldest son James Hampton McGavock (1842-1916)assumed responsibility for the family estate. He maintained the Fort Chiswell plantation and developed a special talent for horse breeding. James Hampton McGavock also served on the Board of Directors for the Farmers Bank of Southwest Virginia as well as the Wythe County Board of Supervisors. He fought in the Confederate States Army in Company A of the 4th Virginia Infantry Regiment.
James Hampton McGavock wed Elizabeth Pointer (1843-1893)(nicknamed Bettie) of Williamson County, Tennessee in 1867. Elizabeth Pointer was the daughter of William H. Pointer. Her only brother Edward Pointer died during the Civil War. Elizabeth Pointer McGavock and James Hampton McGavock had five sons, two of whom died as infants. She died in 1893 following a long and painful illness. James Hampton remarried in 1900 to Evilina Moore of Louisiana. They had one son.
The eldest son Edward Pointer McGavock (1868-1950)embarked upon a medical career after studying at Hampden-Sydney College. He graduated medical school at the University of Virginia in 1893 and settled in Lynchburg and Richmond, Virginia.
William Pointer McGavock married Flora McDonald Stokes in 1894 and moved to Fredericksburg, Virginia. By 1907, William had traveled to New Mexico where his lifelong penchant for strong drink and gambling almost led him to the gallows. While intoxicated he accidentally shot a man and faced lynching by local citizens and execution by local law enforcement. With the aid of an adept lawyer, he escaped punishment. Amazingly, the New Mexico courts released him upon the proviso that he never return. He died in Santa Barbara, California in 1918.
Cloyd McGavock remained in Wythe County and married Annie L. Jordan in 1902. He was employed in various endeavors including a bake shop and the New River Ordnance Plant. His brother Edward Pointer remained the patriarch of the family even while practicing medicine in Richmond and Lynchburg. Edward evidently made most of the business decision regarding Fort Chiswell and the estate of his father, James Hampton McGavock, who died in 1916.
In 1918, the Fort Chiswell Mansion exchanged hands. Edward Pointer McGavock returned to Richmond and Cloyd McGavock settled in Wytheville, Virginia. Cloyd McGavock later married Willie Wolf McGavock who conducted much family business for Edward Pointer McGavock. Edward Pointer McGavock died in 1950 and Cloyd McGavock in 1951.
Scope and Content
The McGavock Family Papers cover two hundred years of family history, ranging from a 1751 land plat of Fort Chiswell to a 1961 tax receipt. A rich and varied collection, the Papers provide researchers with valuable information on the history of Wythe County, southwest Virginia, and Tennessee. Subjects revealed through the collection include land acquisition and development, agriculture, horse breeding, domestic matters, slavery, education, salt manufacturing, and banking. Information on the American Civil War, World War I, and World War II are also among items in the collection.
The collection includes Series I, Correspondence (1787-1950); Series II, Financial and Legal Records (1794-1961); Series III, Land Records (1751-1903); Series IV, Miscellaneous Records (1772-1951); Series V, Books (1826, 1890-1893); and Series VI, Photographs.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence. 1787 - 1950., 61 folders.
  - Folder 1. Correspondence - James McGavock Sr. 1787 - 1800., 6 letters. (Series-folder 1:1)
    Correspondents include Randal McGavock, James Wood, David McGavock, Thomas Preston, John Blunt, and Hugh McGavock.
  - Folder 2. Correspondence - James McGavock Jr. 1799 - 1819., 15 letters. (Series-folder 1:2)
    Correspondents include: David McGavock, Randal McGavock, R. Crockett, John Mallory, James Toncray, Adam Wirt, William Preston, G. Henderson, Andrew Crockett, and Robert Sanders Jr.
  - Folder 3. Correspondence - James McGavock Jr.. 1820 - 1838., 15 letters. (Series-folder 1:3)
    Correspondents include: Isaac Stuart, Alexander Smyth, John Haller, Randal McGavock, Sarah H. Collins, Dr. Jacob Haller, Lysander McGavock, Benjamin Reichel, Isaac Lehew, Ferguson, Jones & Campbell Company, George Kincannon, James Toncray, William Hill, and Jane L. Crockett.
  - Folder 4. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1831 - 1838., 3 items. (Series-folder 1:4)
    Correspondents include: Lysander McGavock and Francis Bell.
  - Folder 5. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1840 - 1844., 11 letters. (Series-folder 1:5)
    Correspondents include: William H. McFarland, B. Moore Company, Ephraim McGavock, T. J. Morrison, Gordon L. Jordan, F. H. Lawson, John Scruggs, H. S. Mathews, and Sayers, Oglesby and Company.
  - Folder 6. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1845 - 1849., 13 letters. (Series-folder 1:6)
    Correspondents include: Morrison, Watkins and Company, Ephraim McGavock, Agnes L. McGavock, McDaniel and M. Corkle, H. W. and S. S. Fry Company, Joseph J. Ramsey, McDaniel and Son, Beverly A. Johnston, and Mary McGavock.
  - Folder 7. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1850 - 1852., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:7)
    Correspondents include: Stuart McClung, McDaniel & Son, J. A. Hopkins, Joseph Cloyd, Mary McGavock, Lee and Johnson Company, and George Watt and Company.
  - Folder 8. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1853 - 1859. (Series-folder 1:8)
  - Folder 9. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1860 - 1864., 19 letters. (Series-folder 1:9)
    Correspondents include: T. J. Morrison, Captain R. G. Banks, Thomas P. Clapp, R. Patton, David Sexton, Joseph S. Venable, M. Aiken, W. H. Werth, Captain C. W. Venable, Charles H. Miller, Robert W. Haynes, M. Clark, and G. S. Williams.
  - Folder 10. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1865 - June 1866., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:10)
    Correspondents include: Isaac B. Dunn, Gordon Cloyd Kent, W. W. Ward, W. H. Crouch, R. H. Crockett, R. C. Crouch, Lee and Taylor Company, and Emma Terry.
  - Folder 11. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. July 1866 - December 1866., 14 letters. (Series-folder 1:11)
    Correspondents include: Lee and Taylor Company, W. H. Werth, Jacob Bonsack, Charles A. Haller, William Richardson, William Napier of Cincinnati, Cumberland Gap and Charleston Railroad, and T. J. Finne.
  - Folder 12. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1867., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:12)
    Correspondents include: John Williamson McGavock, William Napier, Jacob Harris, A. G. Mathews, Samuel Heninger, and Joseph L. Kent.
  - Folder 13. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1868., 8 letters. (Series-folder 1:13)
    Correspondents include: A. J. Huffard, A. M. Jordan and Company, Moore and Scott Company, John W. Gibboney, Jacob Bonsack, John Williamson McGavock, E. S. Trinkle, and J. W. Finley.
  - Folder 14. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. March 1869 - June 1869., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:14)
    Correspondents include: J. B. Painter, Lee and Taylor Company, and John Williamson McGavock.
  - Folder 14. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. July 1869 - December 1869., 7 letters. (Series-folder 1:15)
    Correspondents include: Abie Jouett Williamson McGavock and Lee and Taylor Company.
  - Folder 16. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. January 1870 - May 1870., 16 letters. (Series-folder 1:16)
    Correspondents include: Lee and Taylor Company, W. A. Stuart, V. C. Huff, John Clark, Clark and Tyree Company, Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie Company, Woodruff and Company, and H. Chaffin.
  - Folder 17. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. June 1870 - December 1870., 17 letters. (Series-folder 1:17)
    Correspondents include: John Williamson McGavock, Woodruff and Company, and L. Norvell.
  - Folder 18. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. January 1871 - June 1871., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:18)
    Correspondents include: Michael Caprell, Woodruff and Martin Company, W. A. Stuart, Hahn Brown and Company, J. F. Kent, Daniel E. Wright, V. C. Huff, and Fudge and Gale Company.
  - Folder 19. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. September 1871 - December 1871., 14 letters. (Series-folder 1:19)
    Correspondents include: Ambrose B. Rucker, William and Franklin Company, Howell and Orr Company, R. H. Crockett, Watson and Brown Company, W. R. Stewart, and J. F. Kent.
  - Folder 20. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. January 1872 - September 1872., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:20)
    Correspondents include: L. Norvell, Barnes M. Rucker, F. H. McGavock, Pettyjohn and Rucker Company, and William B. Bryant.
  - Folder 21. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. October 1872 - December 1872, 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:21)
    Correspondents include: Pettyjohn and Rucker Company, Lee, Taylor and Company, and L. Norvell.
  - Folder 22. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1873., 7 letters. (Series-folder 1:22)
    Correspondents include: Pettyjohn and Rucker Company, Joseph Cloyd, Hahn and Brown Company, G. A. Heuser, and Jesse M. Pettyjohn.
  - Folder 23. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1874., 15 letters. (Series-folder 1:23)
    Correspondents include: G. A. Heuser, T. J. Finne, D. P. Watson, Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie Company, Mosler and Bahmann Company, Al Alston, Thomas Wood, Mathew Aiken, James Wilkinson, Agnes L. Richardson, Margaret McGavock, Charles A. Haller, and Jacob Bonsack.
  - Folder 24. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1875., 16 letters. (Series-folder 1:24)
    Correspondents include: T. J. Finne, J. H. Caddall, Taliaferro and Company, Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie Company, C. W. Shortt, James B. Marshall, J. S. Crockett, Robert J. Glendy, and R. H. Crockett.
  - Folder 25. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1876., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:25)
    Correspondents include: Mary Richardson, Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie Company, T. J. Finne, J. F. Kent, J. C. Allison, Thomas C. Basshor, E. L. Osborn, Robert J. Glendy, and H. D. Hatcher.
  - Folder 27. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. January 1878 - June 1878., 13 letters. (Series-folder 1:26)
    Correspondents include: F. S. Blair, James Kent, William Mathews, A. D. Hatcher, Graham Robinson and Company, Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie Company, Francis Bell, J. F. Kent, and W. S. Paulett.
  - Folder 27. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1877., 11 letters. (Series-folder 1:27)
    Correspondents include: William Mathews, Mary C. Richardson, W. S. Paulett, A. D. Hatcher, R. P. terry, S. C. Hurt and Company, R. A. Alston, J. A. D. Myers, and Wood, Kasey and Company.
  - Folder 28. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. July 1878 - November 1878., 13 letters. (Series-folder 1:28)
    Correspondents include: E. C. Deuel, A. D. Hatcher, R. P. Terry, R. C. Kent, W. S. Paulett, Madison Puckett, Francis Bell, Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie Company, William Raper, and John Raper.
  - Folder 29. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. January 1879 - March 1879., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:29)
    Correspondents include: W. S. Paulett, Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie Company, Francis Hargrave McGavock, S. C. Hurt and Son, Robert Button, and Joseph Topham.
  - Folder 30. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. June 1879 - December 1879., 7 letters. (Series-folder 1:30)
    Correspondents include: Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie Company, W. C. Crockett, R. Sayers, J. F. Kent, and Francis Bell.
  - Folder 31. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. 1880., 4 letters. (Series-folder 1:31)
    Correspondents include: Allen W. Talley, H. M. Smith, Jno. T. Hawlett,
  - Folder 32. Correspondence - Stephen McGavock. Undated., 11 letters. (Series-folder 1:32)
    Correspondents include: William D. Crockett, J. F. Kent, Lee, Taylor and Company, Abie Jouett Williamson McGavock, John Williamson McGavock, J. P. Mefe, D. H. Miller, A. Myers, William Napier, and G. C. M. Dondall.
  - Folder 33. Correspondence - Joseph Cloyd McGavock. 1871 - 1885., 8 letters. (Series-folder 1:33)
    Correspondents include: Jones and Brown Company, D. T. Jones, James Kent, Samuel Townsend and Son, Sherman and Culver Company, Karn and Hickson Company, Adam Brothers and Paynes Company, and J. W. Robinson.
  - Folder 34. Correspondence - Elizabeth Pointer McGavock. 1857-1859., 8 letters. (Series-folder 1:34)
    Correspondents include: Edward H. Pointer.
  - Folder 35. Correspondence - Elizabeth Pointer McGavock. 1860 - 1866., 7 letters. (Series-folder 1:35)
    Correspondents include: Edward H. Pointer, B. N. Jenkins, and James Hampton McGavock.
  - Folder 36. Correspondence - Elizabeth Pointer McGavock. 1867-1868., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:36)
    Correspondents include: James Hampton McGavock, Abie Jouett Williamson McGavock, and William H. Pointer.
  - Folder 37. Correspondence - Elizabeth Pointer McGavock. 1871 - 1878., 9 letters. (Series-folder 1:37)
    Correspondents include: Nora Mayes, Sarah Jackson McGavock, James Hampton McGavock, Abie Jouett Williamson McGavock, S. A. Pointer, Thomas G. Pointer, and Margaret M. Genans.
  - Folder 38. Correspondence - Elizabeth Pointer McGavock. 1885-1888., 11 letters. (Series-folder 1:38)
    Correspondents include: James Hampton McGavock and Peirce Sanders.
  - Folder 39. Correspondence - James Hampton McGavock. 1849-1869., 8 letters. (Series-folder 1:39)
    Correspondents include: Abie Jouett Williamson McGavock, Lee and Taylor Company, C. P. Kent, John Williamson McGavock, Malvina Mathews, and William H. Pointer.
  - Folder 40. Correspondence - James Hampton McGavock. 1871-1879., 6 letters. (Series-folder 1:40)
    Correspondents include: E. H. Robinson, S. A. Pointer, Nowlin Brothers and Bigbie, John D. Stuart, and J. F. Kent.
  - Folder 41. Correspondence - James Hampton McGavock. 1880-1884., 15 letters. (Series-folder 1:41)
    Correspondents include: Thomas G. Pointer, Frank H. Levering, F. S. Buchanan, H. S. Buchanan, Jno. T. Hawlett, Augustus Heuser, J. M. McFerrin, C. N. Hunter, R. R. Berkeley, Thomas E. Doswell, C. S. Kalfee, B. F. Counselman, L. C. Irving, D. S. Lewis, and Lee S. Allison.
  - Folder 42. Correspondence - James Hampton McGavock. April 1885 - August 1885., 8 letters. (Series-folder 1:42)
    Correspondents include; D. S. Lewis, W. I. Mann, George W. Dunford, and Ben W. Terry.
  - Folder 43. Correspondence - James Hampton McGavock. September 1885 - December 1885., 7 letters. (Series-folder 1:43)
    Correspondents include: N. Robinson, J. M. McFerrin, Samuel Gibbs, Jacob Harris, F. P. Fizer, John Sickels, and S. A. Clark.
  - Folder 44. Correspondence - James Hampton McGavock. 1886., 15 letters. (Series-folder 1:44)
    Correspondents include: A. S. Williams, James T. Crockett, John Funk, James MacGill, R. M. Crockett, Charles K. Harrison, Sanders D. Bruce, Mrs. C. S. Adams, R. C. Shaffer, Thomas Lewis, Joseph W. Caldwell, William Steele, Isam Connelly Groome, and R. R. Henry.
  - Folder 45. Correspondence - James Hampton McGavock. 188 - 1912., 17 letters. (Series-folder 1:45)
    Correspondents include: D. H. Porter, John S. Sanders, Joseph H. Sanders, Bennett Barnes, W. W. Woodson, F. J. T. Sayers, D. M. Hayes, Matthew H. Maury, Nora Mayes, W. A. Caldwell, William V. Wilson Jr., Robinson Brothers, G. H. Hartsell, and S. M. Thomas.
  - Folder 46. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. 1885 - March 1886., 8 letters. (Series-folder 1:46)
    Correspondents include: Georgie Lindsley, Elizabeth Hayes, Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, and Maggie C. Pollock.
  - Folder 47. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. May 1886 - December 1886., 15 letters. (Series-folder 1:47)
    Correspondents include: Georgie Lindsley, Maggie C. Pollock, James L. Kent, Elizabeth Hayes, Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, W. L. McCraa, and William Pointer McGavock.
  - Folder 48. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. January 1887 - April 1887., 21 letters. (Series-folder 1:48)
    Correspondents include: Elizabeth Hayes, Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, Mary Lejeune Wade, F. H. Terry, and J. Robert Walker.
  - Folder 49. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. May 1887 - December 1887., 12 letters. (Series-folder 1:49)
    Correspondents include: Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, James L. Kent, W. L. McCraa, James S. Rhea, Georgie Lindsley, J. Robert Walker, and Henry Silverthorn.
  - Folder 50. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. 1888., 18 letters. (Series-folder 1:50)
    Correspondents include: Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, Georgie Lindsley, F. E. Robbins, Richard McIlwaine, Crittenden Joye, W. D. Shue, J. Robert Walker, Martha L. McIlwaine, James W. S. Rhea, James L. Kent, and C. T. Hall.
  - Folder 51. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. 1890 - 1892., 14 letters. (Series-folder 1:51)
    Correspondents include: Peirce Sanders, Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, Crittenden Joye, J. F. McKinsky, and John D. Thomas.
  - Folder 52. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. January 1893 - April 1893., 15 letters. (Series-folder 1:52)
    Correspondents include: Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, J. H. Fulton, James Hampton McGavock, and Sarah Jackson McGavock.
  - Folder 53. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. May 1893 - June 1893., 16 letters. (Series-folder 1:53)
    Correspondents include: Annie Lee Bolling, Carrie H. Davis, Lizzie Kent, Mollie L. Logan, Bessy Carter Davis, Sarah Jackson McGavock, John D. Thomas, Lizzie R. Poage, L. N. Randolph, James Hampton McGavock, Millie N. Caldwell, and Sue M. Spiller.
  - Folder 54. Correspondence - Edward Pointer McGavock. 1900-1929., 22 letters. (Series-folder 1:54)
    Correspondents include: James Hampton McGavock, Ed Hayes, Grace Hardee Lovelace, J. Norment Powell, R. L. Barnes, Clinchfield Fuel Company, G. A. Reese, J. R. Simmons, Cloyd McGavock, Willie Wolf McGavock, and Abie Jouett Williamson McGavock.
  - Folder 55. Correspondence - William Pointer McGavock. 1890 - 1907., 13 letters. (Series-folder 1:55)
    Correspondents include: Elizabeth Pointer McGavock, Sue Peyton Kent, Sue Spiller, Mrs. R. B. Merchant, William V. Wilson Jr., William Bernard, Charles Del Bondo, and Fannie Jouett Fulton.
  - Folder 56. Correspondence - Cloyd McGavock. 1901 - 1950., 11 letters. (Series-folder 1:56)
    Correspondents include: Clarence L. Painter, Evelyn Robbins McGavock, O. C. Dutton, Fred C. Main, Roanoke Seed and Supply Company, William V. Wilson, B. J. Owen, Stuart B. Campbell, and J. L. Runion.
  - Folder 57. Correspondence - Willie Wolf McGavock. 1940-1943., 15 letters. (Series-folder 1:57)
    Correspondents include: Joseph H. Anderson, R. T. Stephenson, W. W. S. Butler, Hugh Trout, William J. Lees, Nora Wolf, and Ruth Brichetto.
  - Folder 58. Correspondence - William H. Pointer. 1863 - 1870., 4 letters. (Series-folder 1:58)
    Correspondents include: William Barry and Thomas G. Pointer
  - Folder 59. Correspondence - Miscellaneous. 1827 - 1884., 16 letters. (Series-folder 1:59)
    Correspondents include: Jacob Kinchlove, Charles Austin, Jacob McGavock, Joseph McGavock, Mother, slave of W. M. Cozart, Edmund Norris, Jacob A. Bevrle, Jacob Bonsack, F. Harris, Ephraim McGavock, Sallie B. Pointer, William Gibboney, John C. Graham, John L. Sayers, J. A. Moore, W. A. Moore, J. W. Alsbaugh, Frank. H. Levering, V. C. Huff, William B. Foster, C. K. Beecraft, William Terry, J. M. McFerrin, and John Clark.
  - Folder 60. Correspondence - Miscellaneous. 1885 - 1916., 12 letters. (Series-folder 1:60)
    Correspondents include: D. S. Lewis, James Alexander Walker, Jno. L. Hawlett, C. E. Coffin, John H. Fulton, John R. Robinson, J. P. Cofer, Sarah Jackson McGavock, H. Douglas Fuller, John Williamson McGavock, C. W. Gleaves, and C. B. Moore.
- Series II. Financial and Legal Records. 1804-1942., 53 folders